Finding Aid for Arthur H. Vandenberg Papers, 1884-1974
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Speeches
  - 1934
    - Address on WOOD Radio Network, Grand Rapids., 1934 (Reel 6)
    - 1934 Final 1934 Campaign Speech. (Reel 6)
  - 1935
    - "The World Court, January 18, 1935 (Reel 6)
    - "The 4, 880,000, 000 Appropriation Bill", February 15, 1935 (Reel 6)
    - "International Trade Relations of the United, States", May 8, 1935 (Reel 6)
    - "The Latest Constitutional Challenge" N.B.C. Radio, Washington, June 20, 1935 (Reel 6)
    - "Federal Taxes-There is no Santa Claus", July 7, 1935 (Reel 6)
    - "The Tax Bill is Midsummer Madness", August 14, 1935 (Reel 6)
    - "Can America Stay out of the Next War?" Michigan Press Club, Ann Arbor, November 14, 1935 (Reel 6)
    - "Com. Address for 18th Anniversary of Finnish Independence" Detroit., December 6, 1935 (Reel 6)
  - January-July 1936
    - "We Are at Crisis" Lincoln Day Address. New York., February 12, 1936 (Reel 6)
    - Radio Address on Supreme Court. Washington, D.C., February 21, 1936 (Reel 6)
    - "Layman's View of the Supreme Court" N.B.C. Radio. Washington, D.C., March 2, 1936 (Reel 6)
    - "Vampires on the Blood Stream of the Public Credit", June 19, 1936 (Reel 6)
    - Grand Rapids Campaign Speech., July 4, 1936 (Reel 6)
  - August-December 1936
    - Address to Union League Club. Chicago., August 6, 1936 (Reel 6)
    - September 17, 1936. Constitution Day Address. Chicago (Reel 6)
    - Grand Rapids Campaign Speech, September 28, 1936 (Reel 6)
    - Philadelphia Campaign Speech, October 1, 1936 (Reel 6)
  - Undated, 1936
    - Wilmington, Delaware, 1936 (Reel 6)
    - Scotts Bluff, Nebraska, 1936 (Reel 6)
    - Omaha, Nebraska, 1936 (Reel 6)
    - Ohio Radio Speech, 1936 (Reel 6)
    - Connecticut, 1936 (Reel 6)
    - Final Campaign Speech. Michigan. Radio., 1936 (Reel 6)
  - 1937
    - , "Reorganization of the Federal Judiciary", March 2, 1937 (Reel 6)
    - "More Relief for Less Money", June 22, 1937 (Reel 6)
    - "150th Anniversary of the Adoption of the Constitution of the United States" Detroit., September 17, 1937 (Reel 6)
    - Speech to Joint meeting of Luncheon and Community Clubs. Grand Rapids., October 28, 1937 (Reel 6)
    - "Where do we go from Here?" Radio., November 22, 1937 (Reel 6)
    - "Federal-Aid Highway Appropriations", December 2, 1937 (Reel 6)
    - "Child Labor-Proposed Constitutional Amendment", December 20, 1937 (Reel 6)
    - Veterans of Foreign Wars. Buffalo., September 1937 (Reel 6)
  - January-June 1938
    - Lincoln Day Speech to Middlesex Club. Boston, Massachusetts, February 12, 1938 (Reel 6)
    - Gettysburg Memorial Address. Gettysburg, PA, May 30, 1938 (Reel 6)
    - "Monetary Problems", June 16, 1938 (Reel 6)
    - Address to Annual Banquet, Michigan State Bankers Association. Grand Rapids., June 24, 1938 (Reel 6)
    - Address to Graduates of Union College, Schenectady, NY, June, 1938 (Reel 6)
  - July-August 1938
    - "Cherry Festival Address"' Traverse City, Michigan., July 13, 1938 (Reel 6)
    - Address to Western Michigan Conference of Rotary Clubs, Grand Rapids., September 1, 1938 (Reel 6)
    - Address to National Fraternal Congress. Detroit., August 14, 1938 (Reel 6)
    - Address to the Michigan Conference of Seventh-Day Adventists dedicating new auditorium. Grand Ledge, Michigan., August 28, 1938 (Reel 6)
  - September 1938
    - Address at Ninth Annual Northern Dinner of Miami's Committee of One Hundred. White Sulphur Springs, West Virginia, September 14, 1938 (Reel 6)
    - Constitution Day Address. Chicago., September 17, 1938 (Reel 6)
    - Address to Michigan League of Women Voters. Saginaw, Michigan, September 28, 1938 (Reel 6)
  - October 1938
    - Address to Michigan Republican State Convention. Grand Rapids, Michigan, October 3, 1938 (Reel 6)
    - Address at rally of Lincoln Republican Club at Wichita, Kansas., October 10, 1938 (Reel 6)
    - Address in Sioux Falls, South Dakota, October 11, 1938 (Reel 6)
    - Republican Rally at Columbus, Ohio and CBS Radio, October 29, 1938 (Reel 6)
  - November-December 1938, 1938 undated
    - WJR Radio. Detroit., November 4, 1938 (Reel 6)
    - Duke University, Durham, North Carolina. Symposium on Law in Modern Society., December 2, 1938 (Reel 6)
    - Memorial Address for Senator Royal S. Copeland. Dexter, Michigan, 1938 (Reel 6)
    - Profit Sharing Investigation and Plans, 1938 (Reel 6)
  - January-June 1939
    - "Put on the Brakes", February 21, 1939 (Reel 6)
    - "Peace or War for America", February 27, 1939 (Reel 6)
    - "The State of the Union" Annual Convention Banquet, Manufacturers Association of New Jersey.", May 6, 1939 (Reel 6)
    - Remarks of Carl E. Mapes on AHV, May 29, 1939 (Reel 6)
    - Syracuse Commencement Address, June 5, 1939 (Reel 6)
  - July-December 1939
    - "Homecoming Day" Detroit at Michigan State Fair (2 speeches), September 6, 1939 (Reel 6)
    - Address to Republican Rally at Bay City, Michigan, September 18, 1939 (Reel 6)
    - "Peace and Honor for America", October 4, 1939 (Reel 6)
    - Vandenberg's Statement on Trade Treaties, November 3, 1939 (Reel 6)
    - Vandenberg's Statement on Breaking Relations with Russia, December 5, 1939 (Reel 6)
  - January-March 1940
    - Memorial Address on William Borah, January 20, 1940 (Reel 6)
    - "America at the Crossroads" St. Paul, Minnesota, February 10, 1940 (Reel 6)
    - "Looking Ahead to Next November ", March 25, 1940 (Reel 6)
    - "Reciprocal Trade Treaties", March 27, 1940 (Reel 6)
  - April-June 1940
    - Gridiron Club Address, April 13, 1940 (Reel 6)
    - "Senator Vandenberg Supports Far-Reaching Investigation of Old-Age Problem with Particular Reference to the Social Security Act and the Townsend Plan", April 22, 1940 (Reel 6)
    - Address to Republican State Convention "On to Philadelphia", May 16, 1940 (Reel 6)
  - July-August 1940
    - "Volunteers Versus Conscripts", August 12, 1940 (Reel 6)
    - Address to Michigan Republican Service Men's League., August 14, 1940 (Reel 6)
  - September 1940
    - Speech at Battle Creek, Michigan, September 5, 1940 (Reel 6)
    - "Our Worst Tax Law", September 13, 1940 (Reel 6)
    - Address to Kent County Republican Rally, September 16, 1940 (Reel 6)
    - Address to Banquet preceding the Michigan, Republican State Convention, September 26, 1940 (Reel 6)
  - October-December 1940, 1940 undated
    - Address at Logansport, Indiana, October 21, 1940 (Reel 6)
    - Detroit Safety Council, October 22, 1940 (Reel 6)
    - State-Wide Radio Address. Detroit., October 23, 1940 (Reel 6)
    - National Radio Broadcast. Cleveland, Ohio, October 26, 1940 (Reel 6)
    - "Labor Address." Flint, Michigan., October 29, 1940 (Reel 6)
    - Economic Defense Board", December 2, 1940 (Reel 6)
    - Statement (Speech) of Senator Vandenberg at Mt. Clemens., 1940 (Reel 6)
    - Public Statement on the "Stop Dewey" movement, 1940 (Reel 6)
  - 1941
    - "Speech in opposition to Lend Lease", February 18, 1941 (Reel 7)
    - "Albion Commencement Address" Albion, Michigan, June 9, 1941 (Reel 7)
    - "Extension of Selective Service", August 5, 1941 (Reel 7)
    - "The Case Against Repealing the Neutrality Act", October 27, 1941 (Reel 7)
    - "Churchill was here once before!", 1941 (Reel 7)
    - Address concerning America's national defense, 1941 (Reel 7)
  - 1942
    - Speech on Senate Finance Committee work, March 17, 1942 (Reel 7)
    - "The Truth About Taxes and Inflation", September 7, 1942 (Reel 7)
    - "Freezing Social-Security Taxes", September 17, 1942 (Reel 7)
    - Radio Campaign Speech. WJR. Detroit., October 29, 1942 (Reel 7)
    - "Republican Politics and War", November, 1942 (Reel 7)
    - November 1942, 1942 Campaign Speech (Reel 7)
  - January-May 1943
    - Vandenberg statement on Tugvell in Puerto Rico, January 4, 1943 (Reel 7)
    - Statement of AHV on Florida Canal, March 6, 1943 (Reel 7)
    - Radio Speech for Red Cross, March 7, 1943 (Reel 7)
    - "Farm Prices", March 25, 1943 (Reel 7)
    - Trade Act, May 20, 1943 (Reel 7)
    - Extending the Trade Agreement Act, May 24, 1943 (Reel 7)
  - June-December 1943
    - Letter to President recommending Tax Bill, June 2, 1943 (Reel 7)
    - "Connally-Smith Bill", June 26, 1943 (Reel 7)
    - "The Food Crisis", July 1, 1943 (Reel 7)
    - Statement on UNRRA Sub-Committee, July 15, 1943 (Reel 7)
    - Letter to President Roosevelt re: Social Security Rates, September 14, 1943 (Reel 7)
    - "Baruch Report on West Coast Man Power Problem", September 17, 1943 (Reel 7)
    - Statement relative to Baruch Report, September 17, 1943 (Reel 7)
    - "The Mackinac Charter", September 22, 1943 (Reel 7)
    - "Senate Peace Resolution", October 25, 1943 (Reel 7)
    - Statement on Social Security Rates, November 19, 1943 (Reel 7)
  - January-September 1944
    - "Social Security Freeze", January 11, 1944 (Reel 7)
    - "Subsidies and Inflation", February 11, 1944 (Reel 7)
    - UNRRA, February 16, 1944 (Reel 7)
    - March 1691944 Statement at death of Charles L. McNary (Reel 7)
    - "Social Security", March 20, 1944 (Reel 7)
    - Polish Dinner. Detroit., April 2, 1944 (Reel 7)
    - "Poland's Post-War Status", April 12, 1944 (Reel 7)
    - Statement of Vandenberg for London Daily Mirror, April 28, 1944 (Reel 7)
    - "Petrillo", May 29, 1944 (Reel 7)
    - "Post-War Jobs", August 9, 1944 (Reel 7)
    - "International Peace Machinery--the Dumbarton Oaks Conference", August 22, 1944 (Reel 7)
  - October-December 1944, 1944 undated
    - Statement on Social Security Tax, October 4, 1944 (Reel 7)
    - Michigan Presidential Campaign Speech, October 7, 1944 (Reel 7)
    - Michigan Campaign Speech, October 1944 (Reel 7)
    - October 1944 Final Michigan Campaign Speech for 1944 (Reel 7)
    - Social Security Freeze Statement, November 14, 1944 (Reel 7)
    - "Saving Michigan 3250 000, 000 Taxes", November 22, 1944 (Reel 7)
    - Pearl Harbor Memorial Radio Address. Plea to Buy Bonds, December 6, 1944 (Reel 7)
    - Statement by Senator Vandenberg to Resolutions Committee of Republican National Convention, 1944 (Reel 7)
  - January-June 1945
    - "Let's Win Both the War and the Peace", January 10, 1945 (Reel 7)
    - "Lifting Government Controls", February 25, 1945 (Reel 7)
    - Statement re: San Francisco Conference, March 5, 1945 (Reel 7)
    - "Land-Lease--and America's Post-War Obligations", April 9, 1945 (Reel 7)
    - Statement at death of Franklin D. Roosevelt, April 12, 1945 (Reel 7)
    - Press Statement at UN Delegation, May 7, 1945 (Reel 7)
    - United Nations Conference on International Organization United States Delegation Memorandum of Press and Radio News Conference, May 9, 1945 (Reel 7)
    - "The Charter of the United Nations", June 29, 1945 (Reel 7)
  - July-December 1945
    - Speech to Detroit Economic Club, July 13, 1945 (Reel 7)
    - AFL Radio Speech, September 1, 1945 (Reel 7)
    - "Sanctity of Labor-Management Contracts", November 9, 1945 (Reel 7)
    - "Raise the Iron Curtain", November 15, 1945 (Reel 7)
  - January-March 1946
    - "Report on the United Nations Meeting in London", February 27, 1946 (Reel 7)
    - Speech at Grand Rapids "Homecoming", March 23, 1946 (Reel 7)
  - April-July 1946
    - "Proposed Loan to Great Britain", April 22, 1946 (Reel 7)
    - "Report on the Paris Peace Conference", May 21, 1946 (Reel 7)
    - "The Thorny Road Toward Peace", July 16, 1946 (Reel 7)
  - August-December 1946
    - V-J Day Speech, Ann Arbor, Michigan, August 14, 1946 (Reel 7)
    - Speech to American Legion Convention, August 17, 1946 (Reel 7)
    - Press Release at Paris Peace Conference. Finland Reparations., October 14, 1946 (Reel 7)
    - Radio interview from Washington Saturday night. Interviewer: George Cushing of WJR, October 19, 1946 (Reel 7)
    - [October] Speech concerning navigation on the Danube River, 1946 (Reel 7)
  - 1947
    - "America's Foreign Relations"-Cleveland Foreign Affairs Forum, January 11, 1947 (Reel 7)
    - "American Attitude Toward Polish Elections", January 29, 1947 (Reel 7)
    - "The Republican Challenge" Address before Michigan Republican State Convention Grand Rapids, February 8, 1947 (Reel 7)
    - Budget Speech., February 21, 1947 (Reel 7)
    - "Lilienthal", April 3, 1947 (Reel 7)
    - "The Whole Greek Loan Story", April 8, 1947 (Reel 7)
    - "Pan-American Day", April 14, 1947 (Reel 7)
    - "Ratify these Treaties!", June 3, 1947 (Reel 7)
    - "Borah as a Statesman" at Unveiling of William E. .Borah Statue, June 6, 1947 (Reel 7)
    - University of Michigan. Ann Arbor., November 3, 1947 (Reel 7)
    - Address on Aid to Greece and Turkey, 1947 (Reel 7)
  - 1948
    - Report of the Brookings Institute on the Administration of European Recovery Program, January 24, 1948 (Reel 7)
    - "The Battle for World Peace and Stability", March 1, 1948 (Reel 7)
    - "The American Position" Michigan Chamber of Commerce, April 27, 1948 (Reel 7)
    - Address over CBS. Republican Campaign Speech., October 4, 1948 (Reel 7)
    - Campaign Speech. Grand Rapids., October 28, 1948 (Reel 7)
    - Reception of the Reserve Officers Association Medal., November 11, 1948 (Reel 7)
    - Public Statement on Cloture problems, November 22, 1948 (Reel 7)
    - Message to Pan American Union, December 3, 1948 (Reel 7)
    - "Declaration of Purpose: A World of Free Men", 1948 (Reel 7)
    - "Philadelphia, 194811 [Written letter] (Reel 7)
  - January-March 1949
    - "The Acheson Nomination", January 18, 1949 (Reel 7)
    - Detroit Lincoln Dinner Speech, NBC Radio, February 10, 1949 (Reel 7)
    - "The Challenge to the Republican Party", February 14, 1949 (Reel 7)
    - March 11, 1 "The Debate on Senate Rules", 1949 (Reel 7)
    - National Conference of Mayors, Washington, D.C., March 22, 1949 (Reel 7)
  - April-December 1949
    - Address at Annual Award Dinner of Theodore Roosevelt Memorial Association., April 25, 1949 (Reel 7)
    - Address to meeting of Inter-American Bar Association Ann Arbor, May 28, 1949 (Reel 7)
    - "The North Atlantic Treaty", July 6, 1949 (Reel 7)
    - National Press Club Address, September 15, 1949 (Reel 7)
  - Undated
    - Undated, "Alexander Hamilton" (Reel 7)
    - Undated, "Franklin Dinner Address" (Reel 7)
    - Undated, Address concerning Ireland (Reel 7)
    - Undated, Address concerning Canadian-American relations (Reel 7)
    - Undated, Address concerning St. Lawrence Seaway (Reel 7)
    - Undated, Address concerning recommendations of Joint Congressional Budgetary Committee (Reel 7)
  - By topic or format
    - Speech on Supreme Court Reorganization [undelivered], 1937 (Reel 7)
    - Speech, undated, concerning nomination of Edward J. Flynn as Minister to Australia [undelivered] (Reel 7)
    - Congressional debates [tear sheets from CR] (Reel 7)
    - Congressional hearings [misc. extracts] (Reel 7)
    - Scrapbook containing speeches taken from newspapers, CR, and magazines, 1929-1949 (Reel 8)
- Campaign and miscellaneous topical, 1934-1948
  Campaign and Miscellaneous Topical consists of a few folders of campaign materials and two folders of topical interest. One folder concerns the death of Quentin Roosevelt during World War I. The other is a telegram from John Foster Dulles concerning plan for Japanese disarmament written after World War II.
  - Campaign materials
    - 1934 (Reel 8)
    - 1940 (Reel 8)
    - 1946 (Reel 8)
    - 1948 (Reel 8)
  - Miscellaneous topical
    - Editorial concerning death of Quentin Roosevelt; response of Theodore Roosevelt; note from H. Robinson about fabric from Q. Roosevelt's airplane, July 1918 (Reel 8)
    - Telegram from John Foster Dulles concerning plan for Japanese disarmament, circa 1946 (Reel 8)
- Clippings, articles, and scrapbooks, 1925-1951; 1 linear feet; 25 volumes
  Clippings, Articles and Scrapbooks (1 linear ft. and 25 volumes) documents Vandenberg's life and career. The clippings cover the period of 1925-1951. Except for two earlier volumes for the years 1884-1921 and 1901-1910, the scrapbooks detail Vandenberg's senatorial career (1928-1951).
  - Magazine articles
    - By and about AHV (Reel 8)
  - Newspaper clippings
    - 1925-1932 (Reel 8)
    - Senate campaign, 1933 (Reel 8)
    - 1934-1935 (Reel 8)
    - (miscellaneous), 1936 (Reel 8)
    - January-June 1936 (Reel 8)
    - July-September 1936 (Reel 8)
    - October-December 1936 (Reel 8)
    - 1937 (Reel 8)
    - 1938 (Reel 8)
    - January-June 1939 (Reel 8)
    - July-December 1939 (Reel 8)
    - (Presidential prospects), 1939 (Reel 8)
    - (Presidential prospects), 1940 (Reel 8)
    - January-March 1940 (Reel 8)
    - April-June 1940 (Reel 8)
    - July-December 1940 (Reel 8)
    - 1941 (Reel 8)
    - 1942 (Reel 8)
    - 1943 (Reel 9)
    - 1944 (Reel 9)
    - 1945 (Reel 9)
    - 1946 (Reel 9)
    - January-May 1947 (Reel 9)
    - June-December 1947 (Reel 9)
    - January-June 1948 (Reel 9)
    - July-December 1948 (Reel 9)
    - (re AHV's Presidential prospects), 1948 (Reel 9)
    - 1949 (Reel 9)
    - 1950 (Reel 9)
    - January-March 1951 (Reel 9)
    - April 1951 (Reel 9)
      (obituaries)
    - April 1951 (Reel 9)
      (oversize obituaries and related material)
    - April-December 1951 (Reel 9)
    - Miscellaneous (Reel 9)
    - Hazel Vandenberg (Reel 9)
    - Notebook containing newspaper articles concerning the history of G.O.P. conventions, 1920 (Reel 9)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Scrapbooks and albums, 1884-1951; 1928-1951; 25 volumes
      (most cover Vandenberg's political career, 1928-1951)
      (Not microfilmed; available only for on-site use)
      (Located at AA)
      - 1 (Volume 1)
      - 2 (Volume 2)
      - 3 (Volume 3)
      - 4 (Volume 4)
      - 5 (Volume 5)
      - 6 (Volume 6)
      - 7 (Volume 7)
      - 8 (Volume 8)
      - 9 (Volume 9)
      - 10 (Volume 10)
      - 11 (Volume 11)
      - 12 (Volume 12)
      - 13 (Volume 13)
      - 14 (Volume 14)
      - 15 (Volume 15)
      - 16 (Volume 16)
      - 17 (Volume 17)
      - 18 (Volume 18)
      - 19 (Volume 19)
      - 20 (Volume 20)
      - 21 (Volume 21)
      - 22 (Volume 22)
      - 23 (Volume 23)
      - 24 (Volume 24)
      - 25 (Volume 25)
- Miscellaneous and personal
  Miscellaneous and Personal consists of memorabilia and various other personal material, some of great importance such as the diaries Vandenberg kept while participating in the United Nations Conference which took place in San Francisco in 1945 and while attending the Paris Peace Conference in 1946.
  - Notebook containing excerpts from AHV's Private Papers of Senator Vandenberg, 1952 (Reel 9)
  - Miscellaneous items (Reel 9)
  - AHV will and inventory of estate (Reel 9)
  - Income tax materials (Reel 9)
  - Genealogical materials (Reel 9)
  - Degrees, honorary degrees, miscellaneous citations (Reel 9)
  - Oversize citations and memorabilia (Reel 9)
  - Miscellaneous programs, invitations, etc. (Reel 9)
  - Dedication materials: Arthur H. Vandenberg School, AHV Room (Reel 9)
  - Papers concerning dedication of AHV Room, Bentley Historical Library, 1974 (Reel 9)
  - Printed material largely concerning the Florida Ship Canal (Reel 10)
  - AHV Congressional voting record, 1945-1951 (Reel 10)
    (taken from the Blair Moody papers)
  - Notebook containing record of votes in Senate, 1950 (Reel 10)
  - AHV diary re: San Francisco Charter Conference on U.N., March-June 1945 (Reel 10)
  - AHV diary re: Paris Peace Conference: 1st Session, April-May; 2nd Session, June-July; and Council of Foreign Ministers, 1946 (Reel 10)
  - Scrapbook largely concerning AHV's Alexander Hamilton biography, 1921-1923 (Reel 10)
  - Volume: In Memoriam, Elizabeth Watson Vandenberg (Reel 10)
  - Volume: In Memoriam, Arthur H. Vandenberg (Reel 10)
  - Passports, 5 items (Reel 11)
  - Charter of the United Nations, 2 volumes (Reel 11)
  - Congressional hearings on The Vandenberg Resolution and the North Atlantic Treaty, 2 volumes (Reel 11)
  - Volume: The Congressional Awards; established by Collier's (Reel 11)
- Visual Materials
  Visual Materials includes photographs, a motion picture, and a few newspaper political cartoon drawings.
  - Photographs
    The Photographs subseries includes portraits and photos of friends and colleagues. There are also photos of the United Nations Conference and the U.S. Senate. (Photographs were microfilmed and appear on Roll 11)
    - Awards and honors (Box 7)
    - Campaigns (Box 7)
    - Family (Box 7)
    - Family (with AHV) (Box 7)
    - Friends and colleagues (Box 7)
    - United Nations Conference (with Harry Truman, George Marshall) (Box 7)
    - United States Senate (with Robert Taft, Wendell Willkie) (Box 7)
    - Vandenberg, Arthur H.
      - As speaker (Box 7)
      - Early photos, including tintypes, shots of military parade, interior of his office (Box 7)
      - Portraits, formal (Box 7)
      - Portraits, informal (Box 7)
      - Portraits, early (Box 7)
    - Vandenberg, Arthur H., Jr. (Box 7)
    - Vandenberg, Arthur H., Jr., in military (Harry Truman) (Box 7)
    - Vandenberg, Hazel Whitaker
      - Early photos (Box 7)
      - Portraits (Box 7)
    - Album, With photographs and memorabilia, circa 1895-1897 (Box 7)
    - Oversize photographs: Class pictures, family portraits, formal and informal shots, and photos concerning senate and political career (Box 9)
  - Cartoons
    (The cartoons were microfilmed and appear on Roll 11.)
    - "No Going Ashore" by Dowling, 1948 (Box 9)
    - "Don't Spare the Rod Too Long" by C. Orr, Chicago Tribune, 1948 (Box 9)
    - "The Fable of the Bullfrog and the Ox" by C. Orr, Chicago Tribune, 1947 (Box 9)
    - "Something More Vital" by Poinier, Detroit Free Press, January 3, 1948 (Box 9)
    - "Distracting-To Say the Least!" by Frank (?), August 9, 1939 (Box 9)
    - "I'll Concede This One", by Frank (?), August 9, 1939 (Box 9)
  - Motion Pictures
    The film subseries consists of a 16mm black-and-white film of the United Nations San Francisco Conference. A VHS copy of this film is available for research examination.
    - Film showing highlights and participants in U.N. Conference on International Organization, San Francisco with U.S. delegation at end, 1945; 16mm, black and white, on 7 inch reel (Box 8)
    - Video cassette (3/4 inch) copy of, 1945 film (Box 8)
- Sound Recordings
  Sound Recordings consists of phonograph record discs of various Vandenberg speeches, some of which were given on the radio. There is also one reel-to reel tape of a 1936 radio speech given in the form of a debate with President Roosevelt.
  - Sound discs
    - Speech in Chicago with Crosswell excerpts, October 17, 1936; 4 phonograph records 78 rpm; 7 sides
      (transcribed December 8, 1949)
    - WXYZ Michigan Radio Network, January 5, 1945; 4 phonograph records 78 rpm
    - "Future Republican Party Objectives" (Lincoln's Day Dinner, February 10, 1949; 3 phonograph records 78 rpm
    - War aims speech, circa 1943; 1 phonograph records 78 rpm
    - Pan American Day speech, April 14, 1947; 1 phonograph records
    - "Fight for Peace" (re-election campaign speech; parts I and II), 2 phonograph records 33 1/3 rpm
      (cassette copy in Box 8)
    - "Stop the Drums" (WJR radio speech), December 7, 1946; 2 phonograph records 33 1/3 rpm
    - Report to the People, July 26, 1949; 1 phonograph records 33 1/3 rpm
  - Sound tape reel
    - Senator Arthur Hendrick Vanderberg replies to recorded statements by President Franklin Roosevelt, 1936; 1 reel-to-reel audiotapes 7 1/2 ips; 7 inches (Box 1)
      - [Part 1], [86746-SR-1-1]; (Senator Arthur Hendrick Vanderberg plays recorded statements made by Franklin Delano Roosevelt and comments on issues raised. Recorded in form of debate.)
Selective Index to Correspondence
Acheson, Dean Gooderham, 1893-1971.
July 9, August 5, August 9, August 12, August 13, 1946; January 14, January 24, January 28, February 5, March 4, March 6, March 19, March 20, March 24, March 25, June 20, 1947